<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Category Name="General FAQ issues" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
	<SubCategories>
		<Category Name="RailCOMPLETE">
			<SubCategories>
				<Category Name="Managing RailCOMPLETE windows, menus and ribbon">
					<Entries>
						<FaqEntry>
							<Question>A RailCOMPLETE dialog window is not visible</Question>
							<Answer>This is a common Windows problem which typically occur when you undock  your laptop from a docking station and either re-dock it in the same or in another docking station. Windows gets confused about where to display new windows.
		
A workaround is to click on the AutoCAD icon in the bottom Window line on your main computer screen. You shall see a thumbnail version of the missing dialog window. Right-click on the window and select “Move”. Then use your keyboard arrow keys (left, right) until the missing window appears on one of your active screens.</Answer>
						</FaqEntry>
						<FaqEntry>
							<Question>The Object Manager window (or other undocked window) looks garbled</Question>
							<Answer>This is a common Windows problem which arises when you have multiple screens with different magnification levels. click somewhere in your  Windows' desktop and start "Display settings", then make sure that the "Scale and layout" setting is the same for all computer screens.</Answer>
						</FaqEntry>
						<FaqEntry>
							<Question>The RailCOMPLETE ribbon looks garbled</Question>
							<Answer>This is a common AutoCAD problem which arises when you have multiple screens at the tim you undocked your PC (you closed the lid) and moved to another site, for instance a meeting room with a projector or TV set. When you open the lid again, your ribbon will often we garbled, i.e. the buttons are still there but they are placed at random. The easy solution is to run command RC-ReorganizeRibbonToDefault. Otherwise, you may hold down the Control button and drag the bottom of a ribbon button group (such as "Manage" or "Tools") and drop them at their usual place in the ribbon.</Answer>
						</FaqEntry>
						<FaqEntry>
							<Question>I can't see all buttons in my RailCOMPLETE ribbon</Question>
							<Answer>This happens if your screen does not have enough pixels to show all buttons. AutoCAD will collapse enough button groups (such as Manage" or "Tools") as needed. However, you may hold down the Control button and drag the bottom of a ribbon button group and drop it (undock) somewhere outside of the ribbon, to leave more space for the remaining buttons in the ribbon. To return (dock) a button group again, either click the small icon in the undocked button group, or use Ctrl+drag to move it back into the ribbon.</Answer>
						</FaqEntry>
					</Entries>
				</Category>
				<Category Name="Text box scrolling">
					<Entries>
						<FaqEntry>
							<Question>When editing a number in a text box by scrolling when using Alt as a modifier key, the text box loses focus.</Question>
							<Answer>There is interference between the scrolling tool and AutoCAD hotkey mode since both use the Alt key. Left click the text box to regain focus.</Answer>
						</FaqEntry>
					</Entries>
				</Category>
				<Category Name="Keyboards shortcut and AutoCAD user interface customization (CUI)">
					<Entries>
						<FaqEntry>
							<Question>Double-clicking on a point object used to bring up the RailCOMPLETE Properties Manager, but now the AutoCAD EATTEDIT window appears instead, how can I revert this?</Question>
							<Answer>AutoCAD is the 'owner' of all keyboard clicks as long as you are working in a non-RailCOMPLETE window (such as hovering over objects in modelspace). AutoCAD offers a tool 'CUI' (Customize User Interface) which lets you define what should happen on "Double Click Actions". These settings are stored in an AutoCAD Profile which you can access through the OPTION command. AutoCAD lets you define several profiles, so just reverting the Current Profile setting to the default AutoCAD profile might do the trick for you. RailCOMPLETE has a command 'RC-EDITPOINTOBJECT' which is run as a script from AutoCAD if you define AutoCAD's double-click action to do so. By default RailCOMPLETE will set up macros to do this for you.
							
To check or fix the current profile settings, run AutoCAD command CUI, select 'Customize/Customizations in All Files/Double Click Actions' and make sure that you have suitably named macros (the 'Command Name' and the 'Macro' rows to the right), where the macro should read ^C^CRC-EditPlacedObject (see screenshots below). The ^C signfies the ESC button, to exit any pending commands first.

Your problem may also be that you are trying to load a customization file (.CUI) in addition to the one you've got already. Try AutoCAD command OPTION (_OP) and set AutoCAD as your current profile.
							</Answer>
							<Image>..\..\FAQ\Images\2019-09-06 Customize User Interface AutoCAD menu.png</Image>
							<Image>..\..\FAQ\Images\2019-09-06 Customize User Interface AutoCAD menu - RC-EDITPLACEDOBJECT macros.png</Image>
							<Image>..\..\FAQ\Images\2019-09-06 Set AutoCAD as current profile - RC-EDITPLACEDOBJECT macros.png</Image>
						</FaqEntry>
					</Entries>
				</Category>
				<Category Name="Graphics that 'disappear' from RC objects">
					<Entries>
						<FaqEntry>
							<Question>After editing my RailCOMPLETE object, the 2D symbol graphics disappear. I can still see the insertion point marker (circle with a cross).</Question>
							<Answer>This might be a common AutoCAD / graphics card issue which may happen when you are showing your screen in one of the non-standard visual styles.

Try reverting to 'Wireframe' visual style, using the AutoCAD VISUALSTYLES command (which you mat also find in the top left corner.</Answer>
						</FaqEntry>
					</Entries>
				</Category>
				<Category Name="RailCOMPLETE and AutoCAD speed issues">
					<Entries>
						<FaqEntry>
							<Question>Updating a lot of objects simultaneously, is time consuming.</Question>
							<Answer>When doing mass update, AutoCAD can sometimes use a lot of "overhead" drawing up extra stuff during the update. By setting the system variable GRIPOBJLIMIT to i.e. 10, AutoCAD will not do this drawing operation while objects are updated. You may also use RC-Settings to reduce the "Selected Objects Limit for Drawing Transient Graphics".</Answer>
							<Image>..\..\FAQ\Images\GRIPOBJLIMIT.png</Image>
						</FaqEntry>
						<FaqEntry>
							<Question>My computer is very sluggish and slow. What can I do?</Question>
							<Answer>RailCOMPLETE has many annotation mechanisms, to be found in the "Show" ribbon button group.
- Uncheck the Alignment Manager ("AM", RC-ManageAlignments) "Bind to Selection" checkbox. If you select many alignments with the AM "Alignment" tab open, or if you already had many alignments selected when you started AM with the "Alignment" tab open, then AM unpacks the data from all selected alignments to show them in the corresponding datagrid. This can be very time consuming if for instance your alignments consist of tracks with surveyed data points captured every 10 meter or so.
- Turn off the RC-Show3dPreview tool before you select a very long alignment, or alignments with complicated object graphics.
- Before you turn on the RC-Show3dPreview tool, select your alignments and set the "3D Quick mode" property to "true". This will use standard 3D formulas forrotating your 3D object along the alignment instead of evaluting the alignment's own "3D Offset" and "3D Orientation" formulas for every sampled position for 3D object insertion.
							</Answer>
						</FaqEntry>
					</Entries>
				</Category>
				<Category Name="Manage Stages">
					<Entries>
						<FaqEntry>
							<Question>I am using the Stage Manager (RC-ManageStagesUsingLayerNames), but some of my layers won't show up.</Question>
							<Answer>There is a bug in AutoCAD which quite often causes random layers to remain frozen even if they are turned on by the RailCOMPLETE software. This bug only occurs to layers that reside in XREF’ed drawings. To fix it, do the following: Open the AutoCAD layer manager with command LAYER and find a layer that is currently visible, i.e. the light bulb is bright (ON) and the sun is shining (THAWED). Just click on the sun icon and click again on the snow crystal that shows up to get the sun back again. Your invisible layers are now turned on and are consistent with the current Stage Manager layer selection again.</Answer>
						</FaqEntry>
						<FaqEntry>
							<Question>I am using the Stage Manager (RC-ManageStagesUsingLayerNames). When I select a certain stage as current stage, there are still partial graphical elements which are not made invisible, but I know for sure that these elements belong to objects that are not present in that operational stage.</Question>
							<Answer>A possible reason for this behaviour can be that you have set as current layer (with the AutoCAD LAYER command) the layer that the object(s) in question reside on. When the Stage Manager tries to turn off that layer, it is not allowed to do so due to the way AutoCAD operates – you can’t Freeze the current layer, i.e. it remains Thawed. But the Stage Manager is allowed to turn Off that layer (the light bulb in AutoCAD layer manager goes out), so all graphical elements residing on this Thawed object layer will become invisible. However, if the object – for instance a switch – has graphical elements residing on other layers, say a layer for track center lines, then these parts of the switch will be visible as long as that layer is Thawed and On. The solution is to change the current layer to for instance layer 0 with the AutoCAD layer manager, just double-click on layer 0.</Answer>
						</FaqEntry>
					</Entries>
				</Category>
				<Category Name="Definition of Network Assets (DNA)">
					<Entries>
						<FaqEntry>
							<Question>I made an update to the DNA in my model file, and now I cannot read positions any more. I cannot select objects residing in XREFs either.</Question>
							<Answer>The present RC version (2019) requires that the DNA in XREFs must be the same as the DNA in the model file you are looking at. You can check the current document's DNA version by starting RC-ManageProperties and de-selecting all objects, then look at the tab 'Document', row 'DNA IRI'. You may check the Xref's DNA versions by using the Object Manager. Select the "RC Xref" object type in the left browser section, then add the column "Dna version" to the data grid. Locate a drawing with an incorrect DNA version, open the drawing for write, and start command RC-UpdateDefinitionOfNeworkAssets. In the drop-down list, locate the DNA that you want to update to and select it. Check that there exists a DNA mapping file from the old to the new DNA. This mapping contains info on how to salvage your data automatically. If there is no mapping, then you can try your best to create one with command RC-CreateDefinitionOfAssetsMapping. Some objects, relations or other info might not be mapped correctly. In that case, there should be a 'patch' in RailCOMPLETE which you can activate with RC-RunPatches. This will usually solve your problems. Consult your local RailCOMPLETE superuser if you need more assistance.</Answer>
						</FaqEntry>
					</Entries>
				</Category>
				<Category Name="Position, orientation and offset in 3D space">
					<Entries>
						<FaqEntry>
							<Question>Why is there no (X,Y,Z) coordinate available for point objects in Properties Manager / Object Manager? How can I change (X,Y,Z)?</Question>
							<Answer>RailCOMPLETE has many indirect ways of changing a point object's position (X,Y,Z) in 3D space, but not by direct manipulation. Position X, Position Y and Position Z are AutoCAD's native properties. Press Ctrl+1 to activate AutoCAD's properties manager, and modify (X,Y,Z) there.
							
However, you can access the geographical coordinates for a point object's insertion point, in Lua code, as (geoCoord.X,geoCoord.Y,geoCoord.Z).</Answer>
						</FaqEntry>
						<FaqEntry>
							<Question>3D Position - Altitude or Elevation - what's the difference?</Question>
							<Answer>RailCOMPLETE borrows from the language of aircrafts. The local mean sea level (MSL) is your basic reference. 'Elevation' denotes the vertical distance from MSL to your local terrain surface. 'Height' denotes the vertical distance from local terrain surface to an object (which is usually above ground, but in tunnels you would be below ground at a negative height). 'Altitude' denotes the vertical distance from MSL to your point object in space. Therefore, the CAD system Z coordinate, in the current World coordinate system, corresponds to an *altitude*.
							</Answer>
							<Image>..\..\FAQ\Images\2019-09-20 Elevation plus Height equals Altitude.png</Image>
						</FaqEntry>
						<FaqEntry>
							<Question>3D Orientation - Pitch, Roll and Yaw</Question>
							<Answer>From the language of aircrafts, we speak of Pitch, Roll and Yaw.

* 'Pitch' means lifting or dipping the nose, corresponding to positive or negative railway gradient.
* 'Roll' means that one wing tip is higher than the other, corresponding to railway cant (superelevation).
* 'Yaw' means rotation due to heavy sidewind. For railways, 0 degrees yaw means the 'up' direction, and 180 degrees yaw means 'down'.

The up/down directions in railways are also called 'direction of increasing / decreasing mileage'.
							</Answer>
							<Image>..\..\FAQ\Images\2019-09-21 Pitch, Roll, and Yaw.png</Image>
						</FaqEntry>
						<FaqEntry>
							<Question>I turn on the Position tool, but the transient position info doesn't show in my drawing's modelspace.</Question>
							<Answer>You may have activated the Position Snap mode. If the Position tool has been de-activated and is then re-activated, then you must select an alignment explicitly again in order to turn on the position. Otherwise it would not know which alignment to calculate positions relative to.</Answer>
						</FaqEntry>
						<FaqEntry>
							<Question>The object says that it is located in the center of the alignment, yet it doesn't look that way in modelspace. The DistanceToAlignment property is 0.</Question>
							<Answer>Check if you have tilted your CAD editor view axis, such that the Z axis is not pointing directly towards you anymore. If the object has an non-zero elevation above sea level and you look at it from an angle, then the object will appear to not snap to its alignment, since the 2D alignment geometry is shown as a 2D polyline with Z=0. Use the AutoCAD NAVVCUBE command to show the navigation cube, and click on “Top” to see everything strictly along the Z axis again.</Answer>
						</FaqEntry>
					</Entries>
				</Category>
				<Category Name="Lua">
					<Entries>
						<FaqEntry>
							<Question>How can I check if an alignment has superelevation information (or gradient)?</Question>
							<Answer>When no information is available, Lua may return a “NaN” value. This is a very specialized value, which is the only one that is not equal to itself (!), that is, (NaN ~= NaN) is actually True. The trick is to convert it to the string “-1.#IND” , and to use this string to compare with. See the following example – a local function isnan(x) and an example where cant or 0 is extracted from an object’s own alignment:
							</Answer>
							<Image>..\..\FAQ\Images\lua01.png</Image>
						</FaqEntry>
					</Entries>
				</Category>
				<Category Name="Alignments">
					<Entries>
						<FaqEntry>
							<Question>How do I export alignment data from RailCOMPLETE to Excel?</Question>
							<Answer>
1.	Start RC-ManageAlignments or click the 'Alignments' button in the 'Manage' section in the ribbon.
2.	In the browser section to the left, select the alignment(s) that you want to export data for.
3.	Select the «Alignment» tab and the «Horizontal» sub-tab.
4.	Activate «Extended View» in order to see more data and a data summary, if needed.
5.	Mark all alignment data cells (click to the left of each row, or mark a cell range).
6.	You may click the top left corner to mark the whole data grid.
7.	Press Ctrl-C in order to copy marked cell values to clipboard,.
8.	Alternatively, use one of the right-click menu choices for copying data, with or without column headers.
9.	Open an Excel spreadsheet and press Ctrl-V.
10.	'Infinity' translates to 1e+99 (scientific format in Excel). Clothoids have infinite curvature where they meet a straight line.
11.	You may need to replace decimal periods with commas in order get the numbers right, Excel has special support for this.
12.	Repeat the process for Vertical and for Cant data if needed.
13.	Repeat the process for the next alignment. RailCOMPLETE does not offer copying from multiple datagrids in one operation.
							</Answer>
							<Image Scale="1.5" AllowCopying="True">..\..\FAQ\Images\AlignmentHorizontalExcel.png</Image>
							<Image Scale="1.5" AllowCopying="False">..\..\FAQ\Images\AlignmentVerticalExcel.png</Image>
							<Image Scale="1.5">..\..\FAQ\Images\AlignmentCantExcel.png</Image>
						</FaqEntry>
					</Entries>
				</Category>
			</SubCategories>
		</Category>
	</SubCategories>
</Category>

<!-- C:\Users\clfey\Documents\GitHub\RailCOMPLETE\Customization\COMMON\FAQ\Images\2019-09-20 Elevation plus Height equals Altitude.png -->